

# CONTACT

PHONE +639101204262

EMAIL edseljr.raper@gmail.com

ADDRESS Mindanao, Philippines

#### LINKEDIN

https://www.linkedin.com/in/edsel-raper-259071252/

#### **SKILLS**

- SEO Search Engine Optimization
- Link Building
- Off-page SEO
- Content Writing
- Article Optimization
- Social Media Marketing
- Graphic Editing

Graphic Design \_\_\_\_

- Wordpress
- Web Scrapping 67%
  Link Building 78%
  English Writing 80%
  English Fluency 74%

# EDSEL B. RAPER JR

SEO | LINK BUILDING | OUTREACH | CONTENT WRITING | ARTICLE OPTIMIZATION

# **ABOUT ME**

A freelancer with over 1 year of experience in SEO, link building, content writing, and article optimization, I have a solid foundation in the industry and am confident in my ability to drive results and improve online visibility for my clients. I have a strong understanding of how to create and execute effective strategies to improve search engine rankings, generate high-quality backlinks, and create compelling and engaging content.

# **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# Content Writing and Article Optimization Freelancing: September 2022 - Present

- In charge of creating contents for websites and blogs.
- Update and publish new articles on Wordpress
- Create graphic designs for content writing and blogs.
- Ensures key phrases are relevant and can compete in ranking.

# Link Building and Outreach Freelancing: March 2022 - June 2022

- In charge of creating high-quality backlinks for websites.
- Dismisses irrelevant websites, evaluates metrics, and examines competitor back links.
- Manages Link Building data and analyzing competitor backlinks and outreach of webmasters

### **GIS Specialist**

## NCIP: March 2021- July 2021

- Create digital maps for private and government uses.
- Gather data for processing and formulation of maps
- Lead teams for instructions and data gathering

#### **Technical Writer**

#### NCIP: July 2021- March 2022

• Create technical content for the formulation of Sustainable Development Plan of the government for Indigenous People.

# **EDUCATION**

Caraga State University 2015 - 2020 Ultimate SEO Training
Bachelor of Science in A&B Engineering Udemy 2022

### **Licensed A&B Engineering**

Passer of ABELE September 2022